A Finding Aid to the Robin Forbes Slides of SoHo, 1975-1976 AAA.forbrobi
Archives of American Art
Robin Forbes slides of SoHo
1975 - 1976
AAA.forbrobi
Archives of American Art
0.4 Linear feet
The Robin Forbes Slides of SoHo collection measures 0.4 linear feet and consists entirely of 35mm color slides of the SoHo District of New York City, taken between 1975-1976. Depicted are street scenes of Spring Street, Prince Street, West Broadway, and other streets in SoHo; SoHo faces taken on West Broadway; businesses including the Spring Street Bar, the OH HO SO bar, Fanelli's Bar, Parocelso, The Cheese Store, Clockmaker/Miso, and the SoHo Weekly News staff; gallery installations, including Robert Morris and Robert Smithson exhibitions; artists working in SoHo studios including Margery Bihan, Rosemarie Castoro, Marisol, and unknown artists, and dance performances and poetry readings.
Forbes, Robin
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated in 1988 by the estate of Robin Forbes via executor Jerremiah O. Bragstad.
Biographical/Historical note
Robin Forbes (d. 1982) was a photographer working in the SoHo district of New York City in the mid-1970s. He captured numerous images of street scenes, artists, studios, exhibition installations, lofts, people, performances, and businesses of the era.
Scope and Contents note
The Robin Forbes Slides of SoHo collection measures 0.4 linear feet and consists entirely of 35mm color slides of the SoHo District of New York City, taken between 1975-1976. Depicted are street scenes of Spring Street, Prince Street, West Broadway, and other streets in SoHo; SoHo faces taken on West Broadway; businesses including the Spring Street Bar, the OH HO SO bar, Fanelli's Bar, Parocelso, The Cheese Store, Clockmaker/Miso, and the SoHo Weekly News staff; gallery installations, including Robert Morris and Robert Smithson exhibitions; artists working in SoHo studios including Margery Bihan, Rosemarie Castoro, Marisol, and unknown artists, and dance performances and poetry readings.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. research center.
Existence and Location of Copies note
This collection has been digitized in its entirety and is available on the Archives of American Art's website.
Arrangement note
Due to its small size, this collection has been arranged into one series. Box numbers in the finding aid container listing represent archival slide storage containers housed in one larger box. Within each new container, groupings of slides are titled and arranged according to the handwritten labels found on the original slide boxes. These groupings are listed as folders in the finding aid.
Series 1: Slides of SoHo, 1975-1976 (Box 1; 0.4 linear feet)
Bihan, Margery; Castoro, Rosemarie; Marisol, 1930-; Morris, Robert, 1931-; Smithson, Robert; Slides; SoHo (New York, N.Y.)
- Slides of SoHo, 1975-1976; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  Arrangement note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - SoHo Faces, West Broadway, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artists in Studios, Margery Bihan, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Artists in Studios, Rosemarie Castoro, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Artists in Studios, Marisol, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Artists in Studios, Unidentified Artists, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SoHo Gallery Installations, Smithson/Morris, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SoHo Gallery Installations, Unidentified, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SoHo Performances, Dance and Poetry, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SoHo Businesses, Spring St. Bar, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SoHo Businesses, OH HO SO, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - SoHo Businesses, Fanelli's Bar, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - SoHo Businesses, Parocelso, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - SoHo Businesses, The Cheese Store, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - SoHo Businesses, Clockmaker/Miso, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - SoHo Newspaper, SoHo Weekly News Staff, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - SoHo District, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SoHo District, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - SoHo District, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - SoHo District, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)